<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-07T12:29:38+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Harri McAleese Tutoring</title><subtitle>Tutoring services in and around Manchester M20.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My Subjects</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/subjects/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Subjects" /><published>2024-09-23T19:20:27+01:00</published><updated>2024-09-23T19:20:27+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-jekyll%20copy%203</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/subjects/"><![CDATA[<p>Most topics I offer tuition up to A-Level (or Equivalent)</p>

<h3 id="my-specialities">My Specialities:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Maths</li>
  <li>Physics</li>
  <li>Engineering</li>
  <li>Coding/Computing</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="other-offered-topics">Other Offered Topics:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Design</li>
  <li>IT</li>
  <li>CAD</li>
  <li>Statistics</li>
  <li>Robotics</li>
  <li>History (GCSE and below)</li>
  <li>English (GCSE and below)</li>
  <li>Chemistry (GCSE and below)</li>
  <li>Biology (GCSE and below)</li>
  <li>Essay Writing</li>
  <li>Presentation Skills</li>
</ul>

<p>I am also open to teaching generally for pre-GCSE level students.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most topics I offer tuition up to A-Level (or Equivalent)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How I teach</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/how/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I teach" /><published>2024-09-23T19:00:27+01:00</published><updated>2024-09-23T19:00:27+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-jekyll%20copy%202</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/how/"><![CDATA[<p>How I teach and how lessons work</p>

<h2 id="my-approcah">My Approcah</h2>
<p>It’s important to me first and foremost for a tutee to be comfortable and feel understood. I listen to my tutees needs and their problems to gain an understanding of what I need to address in my lessons. I believe there are no stupid questions, but I don’t give answers for free, instead I believe that teaching understanding means the questions reduce, or get more complex, and both are brilliant. I have often used metaphors and my own examples to help tutees learn. In some cases, there simplpy isn’t interest in a topic necessary under a syllabus. In such a case, knowing a tutee’s interests and how their mind works allows me to build with them frameworks they can see the topic through. If this doesn’t make it interesting, it at least gives them methodologies for tackling it that work for them. The ultimate goal is to help the tutee find a passion for the topic and gain an understanding that makes future learning not just easier, but fun too!</p>

<h2 id="how-lessons-will-work">How lessons will work</h2>
<p>Firstly, I’d like to talk to the tutee to understand them a little better, what do they like/dislike, how do they find the topics they are studying, what interests them. Lessons will be tuned based on how they are feeling with their studies. If they are struggling with a new topic, lets dive in and see what we can do. If something is easy, whats next on the syllabus to get ahead? This way the tutee feels heard and never feels lost or bored, which are key to developing comfort and understanding in topics.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How I teach and how lessons work]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Experience</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/experience/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Experience" /><published>2024-09-23T19:00:27+01:00</published><updated>2024-09-23T19:00:27+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-jekyll%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/experience/"><![CDATA[<p>What experience do I have teaching?</p>

<p>I basically live and breathe what I teach. I have spent the last 3.5 years working on a PhD in Soft Robotics at the University of Manchester. I also do hobbyist research in theoretical biophysics and computing, that involves a lot of coding and mathematics. Staying up to date on science is something I’d do regardless and I am constantly reading textbooks and state of the art research papers.</p>

<p>During my PhD, I have also taught undergraduates topics like fluid mechanics, maths, classical mechanics, experimental coding and data acquistion. In that time I found a real love for teaching, leading classes and explaining tough concepts to people. I also found my passion helped bring people up who found things challenging, and I made sure to speak to those people directly and try help them come out of their shell. I receieved wonderful feedback from students that made me proud of the work I’d done. 
I also volunteered during my A-Levels to teach Year 7 students who had difficulty with basic maths. This was challeging, as the kids assigned to me had behavioural problems, but after a few weeks I feel we had made a connection and they started to improve.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What experience do I have teaching?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rates/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rates" /><published>2024-09-23T19:00:27+01:00</published><updated>2024-09-23T19:00:27+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rates/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="what-do-i-charge-for-my-tuition">What do I charge for my tuition?</h2>

<h3 id="i-travel-by-bicycle-so-i-ask-for-a-5-callout-if-it-will-take-me-longer-than-30minutes-to-get-to-you">I travel by bicycle, so I ask for a <strong>£5</strong> callout if it will take me longer than 30minutes to get to you.</h3>
<hr />
<h3 id="a-level-equiv">A-LEVEL (Equiv.)</h3>
<h4 id="--30-per-hour">- £30 per hour</h4>
<hr />
<h3 id="gcse-equiv">GCSE (Equiv.)</h3>
<h4 id="--30-per-hour-1">- £30 per hour</h4>
<hr />
<h3 id="pre-gcse">Pre-GCSE</h3>
<h4 id="--25-per-hour">- £25 per hour</h4>
<hr />
<h3 id="group-discounts">Group Discounts</h3>
<h4 id="--2-tutees-5ph-off-each">- 2 Tutees: £5ph off each</h4>
<h4 id="--3-or-more-10ph-off-each">- 3 or more: £10ph off each</h4>
<p>An example: 3 student group doing A-level, Total cost = £60 for the group (£20 per tutee).</p>

<p>I offer the best possible service and I am open to feedback. It’s my goal to improve constantly, aligned with the Japenese philosophy of Kaizen, it’s all small continuous improvements to be excellent.</p>

<p><strong>I reserve the right to change these fees. However, I will always give due notice for this if it occurs.</strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What do I charge for my tuition?]]></summary></entry></feed>